FENIL R. DOSHI

RESEARCH INTERESTS

In my research, I am exploring the nature of visual representations underlying mid-level vision by trying to characterize the tuning and spatial topographies of proto-object representations, and the kinds of mechanisms that lead to these representations. To this end, I combine computational models of vision, behavioral psychophysics, and neuroimaging data to gain deeper insights into the emergent neural and behavioral signatures of a hierarchical visual processor.

EDUCATION

Harvard University, Cambridge, MA

2021 - Present

Ph.D. Program in Psychology (Cognition, Brain, and Behavior)

Advisor: Dr. George Alvarez and Dr. Talia Konkle

SRM Institute of Science and Technology, Chennai, India

2014 - 2018

B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering (GPA: 8.65/10.0)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Harvard University, Dept. of Psychology

Nov 2018 - Dec 2020

Research Assistant (Fellow), Vision Sciences Lab

Faculty Advisor: Dr. George Alvarez

<u>Focus</u>: Worked on models and behavioral psychophysics experiments that account for human judgements in intuitive physics tasks and capacity-limits in human visual working memory.

Harvard Medical School (BWH)

Jan 2018 - July 2018

Research Intern, Shafiee Lab

Faculty Advisor: Dr. Hadi Shafiee

Focus:

Trained convolutional neural networks to identify and qualitatively analyze the structural morphology of cells. Optimized the models to deal with class imbalance using class-sensitive training and sampling.

IIIT-Delhi, Dept. of Computer Science

June 2017 - Aug 2017

Summer Research Intern

Faculty Advisor: Dr. Saket Anand

Focus:

Lane detection on urban roads using semantic segmentation in autonomous vehicles.

UW-Madison Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

Visiting student

Faculty Advisor: Dr. Dane Morgan

Focus:

Used bayesian models and neural networks to predict changes in the mechanical properties of steel components due to alloy configurations.

MANUSCRIPTS

1. **Doshi, F.R.**, Konkle, T. (2022) Cortical topographic motifs emerge in a self-organized map of object space. *bioRxiv*, in press, doi:10.1101/2022.09.06.506403.

- 2. Conwell, C., **Doshi, F.**, Alvarez, G.A.. Human-Like Judgments of Stability Emerge from Purely Perceptual Features in Unsupervised and Supervised Models. (Paper in Prep)
- 3. Thirumalaraju, P., Bormann, CL., Kanakasabapathy, M., **Doshi, F.**, Souter, I., Dimitriadis, I., Shafiee, H.(2018). Automated sperm morphology testing using artificial intelligence. In *Fertility and sterility.* 2018 Sep 1;110(4):e432.
- 4. Kanakasabapathy, M., Thirumalaraju, P., Kandula, H., **Doshi, F.**, Sivakumar, A., Kartik, D., Gupta, R., Pooniwala, R., Branda, J., Tsibris, A., Kuritzkes, D., Petrozza, J., Bormann, C., Shafiee H. (2021). Adaptive adversarial neural networks for the analysis of lossy and domain-shifted datasets of medical images. In *Nature Biomedical Engineering*, 2021.
- 5. Liu, Yc., Wu, H., Mayeshiba, T. et al. (2022). Machine learning predictions of irradiation embrittlement in reactor pressure vessel steels. In *npj Computational Materials*, 2022.

CONFERENCE TALKS

- 1. **Doshi, F.**, Konkle, T., Alvarez, G.A. (2022). Human-like signatures of contour integration in deep neural networks. Talk presented at *Vision Sciences Society*, 2022.
- 2. **Doshi, F.**, Konkle, T.(2021). Organizational motifs of cortical responses to objects emerge in topographic projections of deep neural networks. Talk presented at *Vision Sciences Society*, 2021.

CONFERENCE PAPERS

- 1. Conwell, C., **Doshi, F.**, Alvarez, G.A.(2019). Shared Representations of Stability in Humans, Supervised, & Unsupervised Neural Networks. In *Shared Visual Representations in Human and Machine Intelligence (SVRHM) workshop at NeurIPS 2019*.
- 2. Conwell, C., **Doshi, F.**, Alvarez, G.A.(2019). Human-Like Judgments of Stability Emerge from Purely Perceptual Features: Evidence from Supervised and Unsupervised Deep Neural Networks. In *Proceedings of the 3rd Conference on Cognitive Computational Neuroscience (CCN)*, 2019.
- 3. Chatterjee, S., Archana, V., Suresh, K., Saha, R., Gupta, R., **Doshi, F.(2017)**. Detection of non-technical losses using advanced metering infrastructure and deep recurrent neural networks. In *IEEE International Conference on Environment and Electrical Engineering*.

CONFERENCE POSTERS

- 1. **Doshi, F.** & Konkle (2022). Cortical topography motifs emerge from self-organization of a unified object space. In *Society for Neuroscience, San Diego, CA, November 12-16.*
- 2. **Doshi, F.**, Pailian, H., Alvarez, G.A.(2020). Using Deep Convolutional Neural Networks to Examine the Role of Representational Similarity in Visual Working Memory. In *Vision Science Society*, 2020.

INVITED TALKS

• Blitz Psychology Talk, Harvard University 2022

• International week, Pontificia Universidad Catolica del Peru (PUCP) 2022

• Program in Neuroscience, Harvard University 2023

HONORS AND AWARDS

 Fellowship for Students from India Awarded in honor of Prof. Amartya Sen Reimagine Education Award (Silver), Student-led Innovation for Next Tech Lab
 Quacquarelli Symonds (QS), Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania
Best Outgoing Student, Class of 2018
 Department of Computer Science, SRM Institute of Science and Technology
National Champion
 Smart India Hackathon (India's biggest Hackathon)

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming: Python (Pytorch, Tensorflow, Theano, Keras), Javascript, Matlab, C, C++, C#, Java **Experimental Techniques:** Computational Modelling, Behavioral Psychophysics **Statistics/Analysis:** Non-parametric statistics, power analyses, simulation, resampling (bootstrapping), model comparison; factor analysis/principal component analysis, singular value decomposition

LEADERSHIP & ADVISING EXPERIENCE

Mind Brain Behavior Steering Committee

Next Tech Lab, Founding Member and Advisor

Co-founded a student-run research lab at SRM Institute of Science and Technology. Co-led over 160 students concentrating on Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Computational Biology, and Mixed Reality(AR/VR).

SELECT PERSONAL PROJECTS

- Feature-based categorical attention: Taking inspiration from work by Lindsay & Miller (2018), I isolated category-specific neurons in a pre-trained (on ImageNet) deep net (VGG-19). Category-wise normalized activation profiles were computed at the resolution of individual neurons and compared with the corresponding normalized gradient-based profiles/curves. Those neurons whose tuning and gradient profiles correlated significantly (hence had behavioral outcomes) were selected. Further analysis (t-tests) provided a stronger selection criterion. During the forward pass, these neurons are then modulated to improve categorization. An open question is to disentangle the attentional signals carried in feedforward, lateral, and top-down connections.
- Exploring the latent feature space of face representations in a reconstruction-based network using Deep Feature Consistency: Trained an adversarial variational autoencoder on the CelebA dataset. The KL divergence loss was replaced with an adversarial loss (Makhzani et al., 2016) and the pixel-wise loss was replaced with a deep feature consistent loss (Hou et al., 2016). Smooth interpolations in this latent space showed that the model was able to capture certain semantic aspects of different facial attributes.
- Neural Artistic Style Transfer for Videos: Produced results on a frame-by-frame basis and later improved it by initializing every new frame using optical flow from the previous frames.
- **Deep Sense:** A Restricted Boltzmann Machine (RBM) trained on a bunch of different songs by Hans Zimmer to produce novel monophonic music in his style.